

RISHA SRITHARAN

Dedicated Post Graduate Teacher eager to resume full-time teaching career. Offer a proven track record of commended performance teaching higher secondary classes, with a passion for education and an unwavering commitment to optimizing student and school success.

CONTACT

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

No 48/12, Second Floor

Ramagiri Nagar 2nd Street

Velachery, Chennai – 42

om.rishasri@gmail.com

8870294801

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth	09-04-1984
Gender	Female
Husband Name	Sritharan. P
Mother Tongue	Tamil
Nationality	Indian
Religion/Caste	Hindu/Nadar
Marital Status	Married
Languages known	Tamil, English

SSLC - 83.8%

State Board, St. John Vianney's Girls High School, Palliyadi / 1999

HSC (Mathematics Biology) – 54.4%

L.M.S. Hr. Sec. School, Neyyoor / 2001

B.Sc (Botany) – 75.5%

M.Sc (Botany) – 74.6%

Scott Christian College (Autonomous), Nagercoil / 2002 – 2007 Affiliated to Manonmaniam Sundaranar University, Tirunelveli.

M.Phil (Botany) - 69.2%

Scott Christian College (Autonomous), Nagercoil / 2008

Affiliated to Manonmaniam Sundaranar University, Tirunelveli.

B.Ed (Biological Science) – 78%

Immanual Arasar College of Education, Palliyadi / 2009

Affiliated to TNTEU, Chennai.

M.Ed (2 year Course) – First Class (waiting for certificates)

Lady Willington College of Advanced Education, Chennai / 2015 – 2017 Affiliated to TNTEU, Chennai.

EXTRA QUALIFICATIONS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Computer Knowledge: PGDCA

TGT (ICSE Syllabus)

Type Writing: Junior (Tamil &

The Ashram group of Institutions, Chennai / 2014 – 2015

English)

Post Graduate Teacher

RESEARCH PAPERS

David Matric Higher Secondary School, Velachery, Chennai / 2013 – 2014

Antimicrobial Activity of some masses from the Southern

m the Southern Ideal Matric Higher Secondary School, Anthiyur, Erode / 2010 – 2012

Western Ghats

Trained Graduate Teacher

Trained Graduate Teacher

Antimicrobial Activity of the

Smt. Gangadevi Bajranglal Chokhani Vivekananda Vidyalaya, Minjur, Chennai / 2009 – 2010

mass Bryum Paradoxum Schwager

4

KEY SKILLS

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Creative Lesson Planning

Classroom Management

Classroom Discipline

Common Core Knowledge

Time Management

Student Safety

Tremendously knowledgeable botany teacher with 5+ years of teaching experience in a reputed school.

Strong teaching aptitude to accompany the varied teaching experience.

Crystal clear knowledge of all the underlying principles in botany and their mutual correlation.

Thorough knowledge of the major inventions in botany and able to provide students detailed information regarding the same.

Greatly familiar with student's common questions and concerns about botany.

Able to handle all kinds of teaching aids such as the traditional model demonstration and the advanced computerized visualization.

Proficient in using the subject oriented common computer aided tools

DECLARATION

I here by declare that the particulars of information and facts stated here in above are true, correct and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Chennai

Date: RISHA C